A Guide to the Donald R. Griffin papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA164
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1
  - Co-Cu (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Cobb, Stanley - Narragansett Marine Laboratory. Coble, Jerry - University of Tennessee Space Institute; owl sound research. Cochran, William W. - Illinois Institute of Natural Resources; bird navigation. Cocke, William A. - bats in house. Cockrum, E. Lendell - University of Arizona; bat homing. Coggeshall, L. T. - University of Chicago; Theodore Bullock; Howard Adelmann. Cohen, Elias - Bat Banding techniques; mines. Cohen, Jerome - Northwestern University Medical School; blindness, echolocation. Cohen, Melvin J. - University of Oregon; Harvard University; neuro and sensory physiology. Coles, Richard W. - Washington University; Harvard University; Yucatan; Airstream trailer; Doug Quine. Columbia University - wind tunnel equipment; Herman Galberd. Comins, Derek M. - Kaffrarian Museum, South Africa;. Cone, Clarence D. - Eastern Virginia Medical School; bird navigation in clouds. Cook, Marion - Ooltewah, TN high school; bats. Cook, Richard K. - National Bureau of Standards; acoustics and bird navigation; Woods Hole. Cotzin, Milton - Cornell University; Wesleyan University; psychology; Michael Supa; Karl Dallenbach; navigation of blind people. Coudeyre, Fae-Balle - speech reproduction. Craig, Wallace - bird head position. Creaser, E. P. - Hofstra College; Bermuda; lobsters. Croze, Harvey - Simla; Oxford University; crow search patterns; Serengeti National Park, Tanzania; elephant behavior; Peter Marler; Roger Payne; George Schaller; New York Zoological Society. Crozier, William John - obituary draft; Harvard University. Crumb, A. S. - bats in house. Cullen, J. M. - University of Oxford; bat sounds; Jack Bradbury; Trinidad. Curien, M. Hubert - Centre National de la Recherches Scientifique (CNRS); data gathering equipment. Curtis, Robin L. - New York University College of Medicine; auditory equipment. Cushing, D. H. - Ministry of Agriculture, Fisheries, and Food, England; fish echo location. Cushing, John - CalTech; immunochemistry. Cutler, Preston S. - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences.
  - Cornell University - Zoology Department - General (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Laboratory of Ornithology; Dale Corson; Paul H. Geiger, University of Michigan; Schneiderman; Van der Kloot; Adelman; Singer; Blight; Barber; Paul M. O'Leary; Hallowell Davis; Robert Galambos; Arthur Schlesinger, Jr.; John Kelleher; Stromberg-Carlson Company; C. W. Torengren Co.; Trails End Zoo; Teiner Engineering Corp.; Alan Van Poznak; Maxine Moore
  - Cornell University - Zoology Department - Projects (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Office of Naval Research; Arctic Research Laboratory; bat radar; Etna School; Raymond Hock; Navy Underwater Sound Laboratory; Bonaventure Island Bird Sanctuary; Massa Laboratory; Brush Development Company; General Electric; Perkin-Elmer Corp.; Kalbfell Laboratories; Baird Associates; Teiner Engineering; Polaroid Corp.; University of Michigan; Paul Geiger; Philadelphia Seed Co.; Bell Telephone Laboratories; Francis M. Wiener; Atomic Energy Commission; Photovolt Corp.; Veterans Administration; Canada Department of Mines and Resources; Machlett and Son
  - Curtis, William Edgar (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Allegheny College; echolocation; owl vision; Don and Maggie Thompson
  - Curtis, William Edgar (Box 2, Folder 15a)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from scholarly access
  - D (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Daan, Serge - International Bat Research Conference, Holland. Dalland, John - Wake Forest College; neurophysiology. Daniels, Charles F. - animal skins; Phillips Academy. Davenport, D. - Arthur Redfield. Davis, Bernard D. - Harvard Medical School; behavioral genetics; Woods Hole. Davis, David E. - Rockefeller Foundation-International Health Division; Brazil; birds, bats; U.S. Public Health Service; University of Chicago; Montana State University; Harvard University; Huyck Preserve. Davis, Flora - animal communication book. Davis, Hallowell - Central Institute for the Deaf; animal hearing thresholds. Davis, Joseph A., Jr. - New York Zoological Society; Rockefeller University; see also Harvard Biological Laboratories; Miss Duplaix. Davis, Michael - Cambridge University; Rockefeller Foundation; Roderick Suthers; Harold Trapido; bat sensory channels. Davis, Richard - Johns Hopkins University; bat sound recording equipment. Davis, Richard B. - Texas A and M; portable bat detector. Davis, Russell - University of Arizona; bat echolocation. Davis, W. B. - fowling nets. Dawson, William R. - University of Michigan; New Guinea; Trinidad. Day, G. R - Meteorological Office, England; bird orientation; Office of Naval Research. Day, Max F. - Australia; Washington University; bee and bird navigation. Deboutteville, Claude Delamare - Museum National d'Histoire Naturelle; France; bats; fish. Decker, Gary - Rockefeller University applicant. Decu, Vasile - Institutul de Speologie; Romania; LaSalle College. De Gehtt, V. J. - New York State University-Potsdam; rodent ultrasound. Del Vecchio, Philip J. - Paterson Museum; bird migration; New York Zoological Society. DeSante, David F. - Stanford University; behavioral ecology. Dethier, Vincent - Princeton University; International Ethological Congress. Devlin, Joseph M. - University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine; bat flight and feeding. Devore, Russell - West Virginia University; bird migration. deVries, H. L. - fish inner ear; psychology. Dewsbury, Donald A. - University of Florida; animal behavior; University of Chicago Press. Dice, Lee R. - University of Michigan; sound equipment; Parameters Inc.; Roger Amorosi. Diercks, K. J. - University of Texas-Austin; bat echolocation; Lauren Hutton; animal sonar; Navy. Dilger, William C. - Cornell University; film; parrots. Dill, David Bruce - The Physiologist; University of Nevada. Dinsmore, James - University of Wisconsin; bird capture, transportation; Trinidad. Dorst, Jean - Museum National d'Histoire Naturelle-France. Douglass, John F. - Harvard College; radar of bird migration; Millbrook, New York. Doutt, J. Kenneth - Carnegie Museum; bat skins. Downes, M. C. - Papua, New Guinea Dept. of Agriculture; tracking crocodiles. Drake, V.A. - CSIRO; Australia; bird migration. Drury, William - Massachusetts Audubon Society; bird navigation; Tim Williams; Woods Hole. Duckman, Charles - bat food. Duplaix, Nicole - otter behavior; Faculte de Medecine de Paris; Joseph A. Davis. Durbin, Peter - Thomas Barr; bat hibernation; caves. Duryee, William R. - Carnegie Institution; Society of General Physiologists; Cornell University. Dwinell, H. A. - Vermont Department of Agriculture; bats in house. Dwyer, Peter D. - University of Queensland-Australia; bat migration. Dyason, Diana - University of Melbourne; Australia; bat banding.
  - Davis, Wayne H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    University of Minnesota; Lincoln Lab, MIT; University of Kentucky; Mammoth Cave; bat banding, vision, homing; Beebe Research Station
  - de Bellard Pietri, Eugenio (Box 2, Folder 18)
    bat echolocation; birds; National Speleological Society of Spain
  - De Coursey, Patricia and George (Box 2, Folder 19)
    bats; squirrels; Harvard University; University of Wisconsin; Trinidad
  - Dijkgraaf, Sven (Box 3, Folder 20)
    der Rijks Universiteit, Holland; bat sound and navigation; American Philosophical Society; Spallanzani; von Frisch
  - Dunning, Dorothy (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Tufts University; Trinidad; bat lab equipment; Max Planck Institut; West Virginia University; Millbrook; Paul Ehrlich; Jack Bradbury; Peter Marler; Harvard University; Duke University; Virginia Polytechnic; Katherine Ralls; Edwin Gould
  - E (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Eads, Richard B. - Texas Dept. of Health; bat banding; rabies. East Meadow Public Library - ultrasound to repel birds; Loretta Kelleher. Eaton, Steve - bird sensory structure. Eddy, Garrett - U.S. Navy; bird homing; Ellie D'Arms; balloon observations; Navy; Japan; radar. Edelstam, Carl - Swedish Natural History Museum; navigation; Edwin Gould;. Edgerton, Harold E. - photography equipment; filming bats; MIT; Trinidad; Panama; Arthur Palme. Ehrenfeld, David W. - University of Florida; turtle orientation; Rutgers University; Barnard College. Ehrlich, Paul R. - butterfly genetics; Beebe Station; New York Zoological Society; Stanford University;. Einramhof, Franz - Austria; bat ultrasound. Eisentraut, Dr. M. - Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut and Museum; Germany; bat banding, homing. Eiskamp, Edward - caves in New York; Eveready batteries; J. M. Mathes Advertising Co.; National Carbon Company. ElectroSignal Laboratory - equipment; smoke detectors. Elishewitz, Harold - bat parasites; Chicago Medical School; caves in Venezuela. Ellins, Stuart R. - University of Delaware; echolocation. Elliott, Robert D. - American Institute of Aerological Research; bird migration. Elwood, R. W. - Queen's University of Belfast, Ireland; animal communication. Emerson, Alfred - University of Chicago. Emlen, John T. - bird navigation; University of Wisconsin. Endler, John - Museum of Vertebrate Zoology; University of California-Berkeley; animal orientation. Energized Materials Corp. - Q-Energy Film; animal pain relief; W. R. Schumacher. Epstein, Samuel - Spallanzani experiments. Erulkar, S. D. - spatial localization; University of Pennsylvania Medical School. Esch, Harald - Notre Dame University; bees and magnetic field. Evans, L. T. - Montana State University. Evans, Rand B. - Wright State University; bat sounds. Evapograph Consultants - Nicholas Rosner; National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. Everest, F. Alton - Moody Institute of Science; bat film. Ewer, R. F. "Griff" - University of Ghana; bats; nectar plants; Nicole Duplaix-Hall. Ewing, Gifford C. - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution; bird migration. Ewing, Josephine - employment.
  - Emlen, Stephen (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Cornell University; kytoon equipment; bird tracking, orientation; William Keeton
  - Emsley, Michael G. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    New York Zoological Society; Trinidad; Beebe Tropical Research Station; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
  - F (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Fairley, J. S. - University College, Ireland;. Faller, Alan J. - University of Maryland; air flow and birds. Farnell, Frederic James - bats in house. Farner, Donald S. - bird physiology; State College of Washington. Fass, George - films of bats. Faust, R. - Zoologischer Garten; Germany; bat film. Fenn, Roger C. - Fenn School; Bird banding. Ferdinand, Roun - Denmark; Sch. Kjeldsgarde. Fischer, Hans - Universitat Freiburg; Germany; bat larynx. Fischer, Richard B. - Cornell University; World Book Encyclopedia; textbooks. Fish, Marie P. - University of Rhode Island; fish sounds; Office of Naval Research. Fish, William R. - bird isolation chambers; Peter Marler. Fisk, Dr. - reprint request. Fitch, Henry S. - University of Kansas; radioactive tracking of small animals. Fitzgerald, Alan S. - photoelectric instrument. Fitzpatrick, James L. G. - bird flight metabolism; films. Fleming, Bob (and parents) - Nepal; ecology. Fletcher, Laurence B. - Massachusetts Trustees of Public Reservations; Reprints; bird navigation. Flock, Warren L. - radar; University of Colorado; Harvey Savely; Air Force Office of Scientific Research. Forbes, Alexander - U.S. Navy Hydrographic Office. Foreman, G. Lawrence - Rockford college; Bat Stomachs. Foster, Leonard - bats in house; Nova Scotia. Fowler, James A. - George Washington University; bats; National Speleological Society. Fox, Adrian C. - cowbird homing. Francis, Raymond - Williams College; ethology; bird migration; Bowdoin Scientific Station; Kings College; Mt. Desert Biological Laboratory; Woods Hole. Frazer, Trumbull - Yale University; bat migration; bat banding. Freedman, Sandor J. - ethology; bird homing; Peter Klopfer. Fremer, Glen - Stanford University; bat anatomy; Ada Pye; James Simmons. French, Herbert E. - animal combat; Holiday magazine. Frick, Henry Clay, II - primate ethology; George Scott; Woods Hole Marine Biological Laboratory. Friedhoff, Richard M. - evolution. Friend, Judith - Harvard University; animal physiology; see Lab Books also. Frundt, Hans - echolocation; Institut fur Biophysik and Biotechnik-Germany. Fry, Varian - cat and dog homing; Reader's Digest. Fulcher, W. W. - Murphy High School; reprint request. Fur-Fish-Game, Harding's Magazine - ad by Griffin.
  - Fenton, M. Brock (Box 3, Folder 26)
    bats; equipment; Royal Ontario Museum; Carleton University; Edward Buchler; J. R. Roberts; Jim Simmons; Dody Dunning; York University-Canada; Millbrook
  - Fitzgerald, Vera Jean (Box 3, Folder 27)
    rats; beavers; cognitive ethology; University of Chicago; William Wimsatt; Millbrook, NY; U.S. Forest Service; South Carolina; Ross Kiester
  - Folk, G. Edgar, Jr. and Sr. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Bowdoin College; Kent Island; Salisbury School; bats; University of Iowa; State University of Iowa; Bowdoin Scientific Station; Harvard Fatigue Laboratory; Richard Penney; H. T. Hammel; Ray Hock
  - Fulbright Scholarship; Cambridge University (Box 3, Folder 29)
    University of Cambridge; W. J. Sartain; McGeorge Bundy; H. M. Taylor; J. Gray; J. T. Saunders
  - G (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Gaisler, Jud - Czechoslovak Academy of Science. Galler, Sidney R. - NASA; Smithsonian Institution; bird navigation; wildlife monitoring; Woods Hole. Gardner, George - bat detector equipment. Gardner, R. Allen and B. T. (Trixie) - University of Nevada; AAAS. Garnecky, Thomas A. - radar. Garwin, Richard L. - Watson Research Center; IBM; Peter Tyack; Robert Seyfarth; Dorothy Cheney; James L. Simmons; James L. Gould; cognitive ethology. Gaskell, Philip - King's College; birds; blind flying. Gaur, B.S. - University of Jodhpur, India; desert bats. Gehring, Walter - University of Zurich; bats; radar; birds; Harvey Savely; Air Force Office of Scientific Research. Gershinowitz, Harold - Rockefeller University; Klausner. Geyer, Lynette A. - bat detector; Rutgers University; equipment. Ghose, S. C. - Royal Air Force; Ardente Otological Research Unit; bat echolocation; H. J. Round. Giacalone-Madden, Jacalyn - PhD committee; CUNY. Gibbons, J. Whitfield - Savannah River Ecology Lab; bats. Gibbs, Sarah Poole "Sally" - poetry; McGill University. Gilbert, Perry W. - Mote Marine Laboratory. Giordano, Antonio - Museo civico dei Storia Naturala-Italy; bat sound frequency; Natura. Glass, Brian - Oklahoma State University; bat migration. Gleason, Mabel R. - reprint request. Gleitman, Henry - University of Pennsylvania; Science; blind echolocation; Barbara Landau. Glickenhaus, Lee - bat information. Gobert, Andrew - Cornell University; pigeons; George Feliu. Goldman, Peter - Ohio State University; bird song recognition. Goldsmith, Timothy H. - Yale University; birds and ultraviolet light. Goodwin, George G. - American Museum of Natural History; mice skulls. Goodwin, Melvin E. - Emory University; bat sounds. Gordils, Elisa - bats as pets. Gordon, Donald A. - University of Illinois; bird navigation. Gormley, Gerard J. - orcas. Gould, Jim - Princeton University; California Institute of Technology; bird magnetic sensitivity; Jocelyn Crane. Graber, Richard R. - Illinois Natural History Survey. Granath, L. P. - Worcester Polytechnical Institute; sound recording equipment. Gravith, Roryman ? - Karolinska Institutet. Graybiel, Ashton - U.S. Naval Aerospace Medical Institute; sensitivity to acceleration. Great Bear Foundation - Olsen, Lance; animal thinking. Green, Robert M. - Harvard Medical Colloquium. Greenbaum, Joseph J. - Wesleyan University; bat habit retention. Greene, Jerome D. - bat auditory faculties. Greenhall, Arthur M. - Portland Zoological Park; Royal Victoria Institute, Trinidad; Alvin Novick; Panama. Greenwood, George - bat navigation; Panama. Gressley, Gene M. - University of Wyoming archives. Griffin, William Alex - cousin?. Griffiths, Thomas - bat species; University of Massachusetts. Griswold, Mrs. Ely (Edith Caldwell) - moles and mice problems. Groshek, Matt - bat recording equipment. Gruschka, H. D. - University of Tennessee Space Institute; owl sounds. Gunderson, Harvey L. - reprint request. Gunn, W. W. H. - Canadian Wildlife Service; birds and wind turbulence. Gurnee, Russell H. - Explorers Club. Guterman, Leslie - Yale University. Guthrie, Mary J. - University of Missouri; bat banding. Guttman, Norman - Indiana University; animals and magnetic field; shock anticipation.
  - Galambos, Robert (Box 4, Folder 31)
    University of California, San Diego; Army Medical Center; Harvard University Psycho-Acoustic Laboratory; Emory University; bat banding, navigation; Woods Hole; Alan Grinnell; bird tracking; Steven Hillyard; Guggenheim Foundation; Association for Scientific Workers; Barry Commoner; Walter Reed Army Institute; Schwartzkopff; Jack Sargent
  - Gates, William H. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Louisiana State University; caves; supplying bats
  - Gauthreaux, Sidney A. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Clemson University; University of Georgia; Louisiana State University; bird migration; radar; Kenneth Able
  - Gosline, William A. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    University of Hawaii; Woods Hole; Phillips Academy; bird banding; fish; Brazil; Natural History Museum, Stanford; John Hill
  - Gould, Edwin (Box 4, Folder 35)
    Cornell University; Army Chemical Center; Woods Hole; turtles; Tulane University; Johns Hopkins University; Beebe Tropical Station; Sigma Xi; R. Mertens; George Bartholomew; U.S. Army; Panama; Harold Trapido
  - Grant, Harold J., Jr. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Beebe Tropical Research Station; Trinidad; American Museum of Natural History; University of Miami; Philadelphia Academy
  - Graue, Louis C. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Sacramento State College; bird navigation; Bowling Green State University
  - Griffin, Donald R. - Family (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Henry and Mary (parents); Ruth (1st wife); John Hill (cousin); Alfred Redfield (uncle); Mrs. Robert S. Redfield (grandmother)
  - Griffin, Donald R. - Memberships (Box 4, Folder 39)
    American Academy of Arts and Sciences; American Ornithologists'' Union; American Philosophical Society; American Physiological Society; American Society of Naturalists; Explorers Club; Gamma Alpha; National Speleological Society; Sigma Xi; Society of General Physiologists; Society for Neuroscience
  - Griffin, Donald R. - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Guggenheim Fellowship; awards; Committee on Scientific Research Personnel; War Manpower Commission; photograph
  - Grinnell, Alan D. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    National Institute of Health; bat echolocation; Harvard University; Woods Hole; University College, London; UCLA; Alpha Helix Expedition; Panama; Norman Guttman; Theodore Bullock; Western Reserve University; U.S. Public Health Service; University of Texas
  - Grubb, Thomas C., Jr. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Rutgers University; bird navigation; Kent Island; Beebe Tropical Station; University of Wisconsin; Sigma Xi; John Emlen
  - Ha (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Hafter, Ervin R. - University of California, Berkeley; animal sonar; Acoustical Society. Hailman, Jack P. - University of Wisconsin; bird vision. Hall, George C. - bats in Iowa. Hall, Jens G. - Norway; bat hearing; University of Oslo. Halliman, James E. - Naval Air Missile Test Center; bats, supersonic pulses. Hamburger, Viktor - Washington University; bat film. Hamilton, William H., III - Bird orientation; University of California, Davis;. Hamilton, W. J., Jr. - Cornell University Zoological Dept.; Huyck Preserve; bat droppings. Hamilton-Smith, Elery - Bats; Australia Division of Wildlife Research. Hammel, Harold Theodore (Ted) - Arctic Institute; University of Pennsylvania; Air Force; Cornell University; heat transfer through fur; see Projects-Arctic. Handy, Ned - Milton Academy; bat photos. Harbold, Mary - Temple University; General Motors; bat echolocation measurement. Hardy, James D. - Cornell University Medical College; Ted Hammel; Arctic Aeromedical Laboratory. Hardy, M. G. - bats; University of Reading, England. Harlow, Harry F. - University of Arizona; primate behavior; Guggenheim. Harrington, Bob - University of New Hampshire; bats. Harris, Norman D. - Boston Museum of Science. Harris, Ron - State University of New York, Stony Brook; roach neurophysiology. Harrisson, Tom and Barbara - Cornell University. Hart, Ron W. - Ohio State University; bat, bird longevity. Hartline, H. K. - University of Pennsylvania; spectral energy distribution. Hartline, Peter H. - University of Illinois; Ann Hurley; University of California, San Diego; snake vision. Hartman, Carl - Ortho Research Laboratories; American Society of Zoologists; Ernst Mayr; William Rowan; Henry Yeagley. Hartridge, H. - Medical College of St. Bartholomew's Hospital, Cambridge; bat sounds. Haskell, P. T. - Anti-Locust Research Center, London; bat sound pulses. Haskins Laboratories - Alvin M. Liberman; supersonic sound equipment; Paul Zahl; aids for blind people; military. Hasler, Arthur D. - bat supersonic object avoidance; University of Wisconsin; bats; bees; Von Frisch; American Philosophical Society Magellan Prize; F. P. Moehres. Hatchett, Roy A. - bat navigation; Zoological Society. Hatt, Robert T. - Cranbrook Institute of Science; bats in New Jersey. Hayes, Samuel P. - Perkins Institution; Massachusetts School for the Blind; blindness in humans. Hayman, D. - poem from The Atlantic. Hays, Helen - bird tracking; equipment; American Museum of Natural History; Long Island.
  - He- Hi (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Healea, Monica - Vassar College; bats, supersonics. Hecht, Max - Queens College. Henson, O. W., Jr. - bat tuning, audiograms; Yale University; George Pollak; Al Novick. Heimerdinger, Mary A. - bird homing; Yale Conservation Program; Auk. Heinrich, Bernd - University of California, Berkeley; bee swarms; University of Vermont. Heintzelman, Donald S. - New Jersey State Museum; bird migration; National Science Foundation. Hellwig, Hannelone ? - Cornell University; Germany. Hemenway, Harriett L. (Mrs. Augustus) - bats. Hendrickson, Joe R. - Vanderbilt University; bird homing. Hendryks, Ferdinand - bird navigation. Henning, Otto - Urania Berlin; German. Henson, O. W., Jr. - bat tuning, audiograms; Yale University; George Pollak; Al Novick. Herreid, Clyde F., III - Johns Hopkins University; rabies; Texas. Herschberger, Ruth - bat repellents. Hersh, A. H. - Western Reserve University; bat demonstrations. Hewitt, Edward R. - Hiram Maxim; bat direction hearing. Hickling, Robert - General Motors Research Laboratories; bat echoes; Mary Harbold. Hillman, Herbert - Swarthmore College; assistantship at Cornell University; Scotland. Hind, J. E. - University of Wisconsin; electrical responses to sound. Hinde, Robert A. - Cambridge University Medical Research Council; Ariane Etienne. Hines, C. O. - University of Toronto; birds and gravity waves; Nature. Hirsch, Jerry - University of Illinois; Animal Behavior Society; Robert Hinde.
  - Hoc-Hut (Box 5, Folder 45)